dumbbells are one of these staples of a
good home gym but they do tend to
dominate a good amount of space
adjustable dumbbells are going to
essentially eliminate that problem but
there's a lot for you to choose from so
it can be a little tough when going to
find which one is best for you I've been
using the smart fit nuobel adjustable
dumbbells for a while now and I have a
lot to share with you all in today's
review
what's up everybody it's Jake you know
where I am the barbin garage gym and
I've got another review teed up and
ready to go for y'all today the smart
fit new Abel adjustable dumbbells in
this video I'm going to take you through
everything these dumbbells have to offer
from the price some of the features as
well as the pros and cons and who should
or maybe should not add these to their
home gym but you know how this goes too
before I get going I gotta let you know
we've reviewed a good amount of
adjustable dumbbells on barbin.com and
if you want to browse our best list just
go ahead and search bar Bend best
adjustable dumbbells our list is going
to pull right up for you and you can
find out which ones that we like the
best
foreign
okay so let's talk about what I like
about the nuo bills for starters they're
adjustable dumbbells so they're going to
take up minimal space in your home which
is really nice you know each one of
these individually it only takes up a
little bit more space than a shoebox
would so you don't have to you know make
a whole lot of adjustments move things
around just to add these to your home
now once again they are adjustable and
it's super easy to adjust the weight as
well so there's five pound increments
with these and you can tell
I'm just flying through these
adjustments right here a lot of times
with adjustable dumbbells you know they
tend to get stuck on you it could be a
little difficult just to transition from
weight to weight and that's something
that I haven't experienced with these
dumbbells and I don't think you will
either and these that I have in front of
you right now these range from five to
eighty pounds so they're gonna replace
16 individual dumbbells which is really
nice it allows you to add a couple more
pieces of equipment to your gym because
you don't have to worry about a dumbbell
storage rack at all with these once
again these range from 5 to 80 pounds
but there's also a 5 to 50 pound option
for you to purchase so that's nice you
just get a little bit of variety with
the new avails
foreign
let's talk about some of the issues that
I noticed that you also might experience
with the nuo bills they feel pretty
durable when I'm working out with them
in my hands but I gotta say they're
likely not as durable as your
traditional dumbbell you know especially
a rubber coated one or maybe even a
urethane one so I'll just try to prevent
from dropping these on the ground
there's a little bit of plastic used
right here to keep the plate and the
handle together as one piece and you
know that could be a cause for concern
for some people as well you know if
you're training to failure a lot of
times people with dumbbells tend to drop
them and that's something you just
really don't want to do with these
dumbbells
[Music]
okay so I spoke about price a little bit
with the newer bills but let's expand on
that now so the 5 to 50 pound bells
those are priced right around 600 bucks
these 5 to 80s are around 750 and the
stands once again are not included with
your purchase so with the stands you
have two different color options to
choose from Gray or black the gray stand
is Priced Right Around 185 bucks while
this black one's about 195. now they do
the exact same there's no difference
between the two of them that's really
just going to boil down to how you want
them to look now I know you could be
spending over a thousand dollars on
these newer bells and I'm not saying
that's cheap I know it's kind of
expensive but when you compare the fact
that these are going to replace 16
different dumbbells in your home they're
going to be cheaper as well especially
if you were to add those one at a time
because shipping but also they're going
to be a little bit cheaper than if you
went with a full set from a company
company that offers their set in this
same weight range so when it's all said
and done this is actually a pretty solid
value because they take up minimal space
in your home they feel pretty sturdy in
your hand and like I said they're going
to replace 16 different dumbbells if you
went for the 5 to 80 pound option right
here
if you're tight on space or maybe you
just don't want a bunch of dumbbells
lying around your home this is a pretty
good option to consider because like I
said you're going to be saving money
especially once you tack on the
additional price of finding yourself a
dumbbell storage rack for your home gym
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the nuo bells let's start this off
with the footprint and how much space
you're going to need for these to be in
your home gym each one individually is
only about eight inches wide and around
19 inches or so in length now when
they're together you know you're gonna
need about 18 19 inches or so because
you'd want to have a nice little space
between the two of them it's just
something worth remembering and it
really doesn't take up a whole lot of
space when you put it into perspective
like that the handle is fully knurled I
wasn't able to find the exact diameter
for y'all but compared to some other
dumbbells I've used in the past it seems
to be around 30 millimeters or so so I
think it's going to feel pretty good in
your hands especially that fully knurled
handle right there it's going to give
you a nice little grip it's Chrome
plated so it's going to look pretty good
it's also going to provide a little bit
of protection from rust and corrosion
but probably just want to clean it every
so often just to keep them in good shape
the head heads are rounded right here I
don't know what they're made of but they
feel really durable and they're you know
like I said pretty durable so you don't
want them to fall on your toe that's
gonna hurt but the plastic right here in
between you know the two heads it's
going to hold them together might not be
the most durable thing in the world so
just be careful with them try not to
drop them too much and the stands are
also made out of plastic so once again
just be careful don't slam your
dumbbells down in here because you might
crack it break it and that's obviously
something that you don't want
foreign
let's talk a little bit more about the
features now maybe my favorite thing
about the nuo bills is just how easy it
is to adjust the weight I mean as you
can see I'm flying through these weight
options right here I just went from 5 to
80 in a matter of seconds that was super
easy but it's also really easy to see
which way you need to go to adjust the
weight so there's a plus and a minus
right here it's going to tell you which
way to rotate the handle to in fact
adjust your weight accordingly and
there's also an indicator on both ends
of the handle that's just going to tell
you exactly what weight you're working
with and really just eliminating any
confusion whatsoever that's a really
nice touch and you know once again the
handle is not ergonomically shaped if
you don't know what that means ergon
with shaped handle is thicker in the
middle than it is on the ends since you
don't have a whole lot of working room
with these nuo bells right here just
something that probably couldn't be done
I personally like it but I understand
why somebody might not and also prefer
an ergonomically shaped handle
[Music]
around these nuo bells now let's start
with the handle I personally like the
fact that it's not ergonomically shaped
I don't really like my dumbbells to be
thicker in the middle so that's a nice
touch for me personally they're fully
knurled and it seems to have a chrome
plating on here which is makes them look
good and it's going to prevent a little
bit of rust and corrosion from forming
in terms of changing the weight it's my
favorite thing about these dumbbells
it's super easy I mean that's about as
effortless as it could be another really
cool thing here is that you do have
indicators telling you which way to turn
the handle to adjust the weights to get
that exact weight that you want and you
also have indicators that are going to
tell you you know which weight you have
which one you're working with which is
pretty nice too now the plates here are
really durable you don't want that
falling on your toe that's going to hurt
but everything else you know there's a
little bit of plastic used to hold the
plates and the handle together as well
as for the stands so you just want to be
a little bit cautious here because the
last thing you want is for these to
break on you
so who should purchase the nuo bells
well if you're tight on space or you
know maybe you just don't want a ton of
dumbbells lying around I think you're
going to really love the fact that these
don't require a whole lot of space I
mean they're only going to take up a
little bit more space than a shoebox
would so that's really nice and plus
it's super easy to adjust the weight
here so I don't think you're ever gonna
have to worry about the mechanism in
here getting stuck on you and preventing
you from really using them and adjusting
the weight on you at all and you know
once again about space you know this
five to eighty pound option right here
that's going to replace 16 individual
dumbbells in your home so that's really
nice because you're going to save money
in the long run instead of buying those
individually foreign
okay so who should not purchase the new
bills well I know they're going to be
cheaper than buying a full set of
dumbbells but you still might be
spending a thousand dollars or so if you
were to go for the five to eighty pound
option that we have right here so if
that falls out of your price range you
know there's other ones out there that
are less expensive than these but they
also might not last you as long so
that's just you know pros and cons a
little bit right there they do feel
pretty durable in my hands but I gotta
say you know there is a good amount of
plastic here in the stand as well as to
hold the plates and the handle together
so they're probably not going to be as
durable as a traditional dumbbell so you
do run the risk of causing some
irreversible damage to these and that's
something you obviously do not want to
happen at all and if you need more than
80 pounds you know it's just you're not
going to get that here so at that point
you're better off just going to get
yourself some traditional dumbbells just
to accommodate to your strength foreign
[Music]
Bells these are awesome in my opinion
it's super easy to adjust the weight you
have 80 pounds to work with and they're
going to replace 16 individual dumbbells
in your home by taking up a fraction of
the footprint and they're also going to
be a little bit cheaper too in the long
run and since there is a good amount of
plastic mixed in right here with the
stand and you know to hold the plates
and the handle together I don't think
they're going to be as durable as a
rubber coated dumbbell or a urethane
dumbbell for that matter so just
something to remember you're going to
want to be a little bit more careful
with these right here thanks for
watching everybody I hope this video was
helpful helped you learn a little bit
more about the nuo bells you know as
always stay on the lookout for my next
review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
this product just search bar Bend new
Avail adjustable dumbbell review and
that article is going to pull right up
for you I'll see y'all next time
foreign
[Music]